Guide to the Harry H. Love papers, 1907-1964.
Love, Harry H. papers, 1907-1964.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harry H. Love papers, 1907-1964.
21-28-890
Harry H. (Harry Houser) Love, 1880-1966.
15 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, photographs, plans, statistical data, notes, scientific papers, speeches, radio talks, articles, photographs, minutes, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include correspondence, reports, photographs, plans, statistical data, notes, and scientific papers pertaining mainly to the work done in China and Thailand and at Cornell by Professor Love, a specialist in cereal breeding and the application of statistical methods to agricultural research; papers concerning China relate mainly to agricultural research, extension work, and reconstruction at the University of Nanking, the needs and problems of that university, particularly during the Japanese occupation, the studies of Nanking graduate students at Cornell, the field work and studies of Chinese trainees at Cornell and in American industry, and assistance Love gave to Chinese agronomists; also, speeches, radio talks, articles, and various papers, including the manuscript of "The Cornell-Nanking Story" by Love and John H. Reisner.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harry H. Love was a professor of Plant Breeding at Cornell University; department chairman, 1944-1949; special consultant in plant breeding, University of Nanking, 1925, 1929; advisor in agriculture and crop improvement to the Chinese Ministry of Industries and special lecturer at the University of Nanking and the Central University, 1931-1934; advisor at the agricultural experiment station, University of Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras, 1939, 1940; member of the Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction of China, 1949-1950; and advisor in rice breeding, Thailand, 1950-1956.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include correspondence, reports, photographs, plans, statistical data, notes, and scientific papers pertaining mainly to the work done in China and Thailand and at Cornell by Professor Love, a specialist in cereal breeding and the application of statistical methods to agricultural research; papers concerning China relate mainly to agricultural research, extension work, and reconstruction at the University of Nanking, the needs and problems of that university, particularly during the Japanese occupation, the studies of Nanking graduate students at Cornell, the field work and studies of Chinese trainees at Cornell and in American industry, and assistance Love gave to Chinese agronomists; also, speeches, radio talks, articles, and various papers, including the manuscript of "The Cornell-Nanking Story" by Love and John H. Reisner; and photographs and printed matter; also, correspondence, minutes, and reports relating to organizations in which Love participated, among them Rotary International, Agricultural Missions, Inc., the Advisory Committee for Foreign Students at Cornell, the Cosmopolitan Club at Cornell, the Ithaca Presbyterian Church, the American Society of Agronomy, Sigma Xi, and Tau Kappa Epsilon fraternity, as Cornell chapter advisor and chairman (1934-1935) of its court of inquiry.
Love's correspondence (1926-1949) contains numerous references to the military and political situation in China, in particular the looting of Nanking in 1927, the Japanese bombing of that city and its fall in 1937, the plight of refugees during World War II, and the rise of the Communists to power; post-war letters comment occasionally on the operation of American economic and technical assistance programs in underdeveloped countries; a few letters are concerned with the missionary work of American Protestants in China, Syria, and Thailand. Also, a two page record of a conversation between Love and Henry Munger regarding the application of statistics to plant breeding, 1962. Correspondents include S. Neale Alter, Sanford Atwood, A. J. Bowen, J. Lossing Buck, Pearl S. Buck, Y. G. Chen, Y. S. Chen, T. H. Chien, Owen L. Dawson, B. A. Garside, Burgoyne L. Griffing, J. B. Griffing, G. Weidman Groff, Raymond S. Hall, Margaret Higgins, Donald C. Kerr, J. R. King, Carl E. Ladd, Kung Ksiang Lin, Walter K. Lowdermilk, Albert R. Mann, Clyde H. Myers, William I. Myers, Jared T. Newman, Bill Pan, Robert L. Pendleton, R. H. Porter, Frank W. Price, Elsie M. Priest, John H. Reisner, George E. Ritchey, Horace W. Ryburn, Knowles A. Ryerson, T. H. Shen, K. S. Sie, Burl Alva Slocum, Louis C. Smythe, Sao-ke Alfred Sze, P. W. Tsou, and Roy W. Wiggans.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Love, Harry H., 1880-1966.; Alter, S. Neale.; Atwood, Sanford.; Bowen, A. J.; Buck, John Lossing, 1890-1975; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Chen, Y. G.; Chen, Y. G.; Chien, T. H.; Dawson, Owen L.; Garside, B. A.; Griffing, Burgoyne L.; Griffing, J. B.; Groff, G. Weidman.; Hall, Raymond S.; Higgans, Margaret.; Kerr, Donald C.; King, J. R.; Ladd, Carl E., 1888-1943.; Lin, Kung Ksiang.; Lowdermilk, Walter Clay, 1888-1974.; Mann, Albert Russell, 1880-1947.; Munger, Henry.; Myers, Clyde H.; Myers, William Irving, 1891-1976.; Newman, Jared T. (Jared Treman), 1855-1937.; Pan, Bill.; Pendleton, Robert L.; Porter, R. H.; Price, Frank W.; Priest, Elsie M.; Reisner, John Henry, b.1888.; Ritchey, George F.; Ryburn, Horace W.; Ryerson, Knowles A.; Shen, T. H.; Sie, K. S.; Slocum, Burl Alva.; Smythe, Louis C.; Sze, Sao-ke Alfred, 1877-1958.; Tson, P. W.; Wiggans, Roy W.; Agricultural Missions.; American Society of Agronomy.; Cornell University.Advisory Committee for Foreign Students.; Cosmopolitan Club (Cornell University).; Ithaca Presbyterian Church (N.Y.); Jinling da xue.; National Central University.; Rotary International.; Sigma Xi (Cornell University); Tau Kappa Epsilon.
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Economic assistance.; Missionaries.; Agriculturalists.; College teachers.
Places:
China--Study and teaching (Higher); Nanking (China)--History.; Syria.; Thailand.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Nanking Alumni - Old China Hands. 1936-1942. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agricultural Education Foundation (correspd.) with Felton Bristol, Reisner 1928-1929. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence -A- 1926-1947. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence -B- Bowen, A. J. (President, University of Nanking), 1925-1935.
  - Advance of Southern forces; no confidence in Northern soldiers., Nov. 15, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Written on board U.S. gunboat, re: looting and disorders. 4 pp. mimeo., Mar. 26, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Follow-ups re: conditions in China., June 3, 1927, Oct. 1, Dec. 5, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - One long letter to Dr. Bowen from Elsie Priest [q.v.], concerning staff and program; encl. in Bowen to Love, Nov. 24., Nov. 19, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Political situation., Jan. 17, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence Buck, Dr. J. Lossing and Buck, Pearl S., 1927-1947.
  - 8 pp. typed carbon re: events in Nanking in Mar.; written from Unzen, Japan. Signed by Pearl Buck. Southern troops said to be the looters., Apr. 13, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Some explanation for behavior of troops (left wing of Kuomintang); written from Unzen. From JLB, Apr. 15, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALS from Pearl Buck; written from near Kobe., July 21, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence -C- 1929-1949. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Caldwell, Oliver J. (field representative, U. of Nanking, New York City office), 1937-1940.
  - Mimeo of cablegram received through the Department of State re: bombing of West China Campus., June 18, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Chang, C. W., Nanking, China 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Chang, R. C., Nanking, China 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Chang, T. R., Nanking, China 1929-1937. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chang, W. F. 1937. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Chang, W, T. Nanking, China 1930-1946. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Chang, Y. W. Nanking, China 1935. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Chao, L. F. Nanking, China 1929-1943. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Chen, K. P. 1930-1946. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chen, Y. G. (President, Nanking University), 1929-1949. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Informal report (poor carbon) of conference held in Nanking to discuss the proposed North China Agricultural Institute; submitted by Elsie M. Priest; * 5 pp. letter re: same, from Chen to HHL. (Miss Priest was Treasurer of the Chengtu branch of Shantung Christian University in 1947; see letterhead of letter of 1/22/47 in Box 1, #2609.), Jan. 18, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report on political situation; student radicalism - northern schools problem of land registration, incl. Univ. property - new law., Jan. 15, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter reporting on first bombing of Nanking by Japanese planes; bombing of Sept. 19; question of moving the University - morale., Oct. 25, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Refers back to fall of Nanking in Dec. 1937; work maintained at West China Union University at Chengtu., Jan. 17, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Raids; financial worries., Sept. 29, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Inflation., May 21, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Visit to Cornell., Sept. 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Return to Nanking campus from Chengtu., July 31, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Last letter; city quiet "since Liberation Day"; religious activities continue as usual., Dec. 6, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chen, Y. S.
  1929, report on cotton improvement studies at U. of Nanking. Scattered comments on political and military situation; problems of flood and drought; some from Peiping, 1939. Nanking, 1944; working in import-export, Shanghai, 1946-1950.
  - 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chen, Y. S. 1936-1937. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chen, Y. S. 1938-1939. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chen, Y. S. 1940-1950. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chien, T. H. (Vice-Director of National Ag. Research Bureau, Nanking), 1929-1938. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Mainly agricultural research, but letter of Sept. 4, 1937 refers to Japanese bombing.
- Chinese Embassy, Hu-shih, Washington, B. C. 1942. Routine requests, ans. by secretary. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- China Institute in America. New York 1939-1946. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cornell in China 1938-1948. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Dawson, Owen L. Shanghai, China. 1936-1942. Letter referring to situation Shanghai, Feb. 26, 1938. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Evans, C. A. 1930-1947. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Fong, P. C. 1929-1935. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Feng, C. F. 1934-1944. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Garside, B. A. (Secretary-Treasurer, China Union University), 1929-1941. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Mainly administrative correspondence. N. b. July 25, 1936, 3 pp. letter re: particular problems to be encountered at Cheeloo because of the "notorious" conservatism of Shantung province.
- Groff, G. W. (Professor of Horticulture), Canton, China, 1935-1943.
  - 4 pp. printed letter to his friends from G. W. G., Lingnan Univ., Canton, China, reporting on the state of work; refugee conditions. File is mainly professional correspondence on horticultural subjects., Feb. 25, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Gunn, S. K., 1934-1936. Rockefeller Foundation. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Hall, Raymond S., Nanking, China, 1934-1940.
  - Typed carbon of letter from Tientsin, re: Japanese occupation., Aug. 24, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Chengtu., Dec. 28, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Heh, C. M., 1926-1929. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Heh, C. M., 1930-1944. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Henry, James M., Canton, China, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Higgins, Miss Margaret, Nanking, China, 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Considerable comment on staff members and various situations at U. of N. in fall of 1934 and 1935, including mention of the Bucks.
- Higgins, Miss Margaret, Nanking, China, 1936-1949.
  - Student demonstrations., Jan. 11, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Enclosing clipping re execution of Feng Jui [Rui?], CU Ph. D. in Canton, Sept. 9th, for "corruption. ", Sept. 1936 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Newsletter giving details of events from time of first air raid, Sunday, Aug. 15th, 6 pp. typescript. Very interesting; written after arrival in Seattle on Sept. 22nd., Oct. 16, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Ku, Shih, Peiping, China, 1935-1938. CC's of HHL's letters; one calling card and printed notice from Hu Shih. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Kung, K. K., Nanking, China 1934-1943. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Kuo, Dean T. S., 1925-1929. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Kwan, Mrs. T. L., 1934-1948. (Box 1, Folder 4l)
- Li, H. H., Tsinan, China, 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Li, H. W., Wuchang, China, 1935-1950. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Li, Jerome C. R., 1950. (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Lin, Kung Ksiang, 1941-1946.
  - Newsletter apparently typed in US from an original which had been snipped here and there by censors; written from National Szechuan University, Chengtu, re: refugee problems, development of China into a democratic nation, which he thinks "inevitable"; U. S. air and ground troops in Chengtu; Chinese students' views of Americans., Sept. 3, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Marriage, surrender of Japan. Mimeo newsletter., Sept. 5, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Return to Lingnan University in Canton.; inflation; fighting between Nationalists and Communists., Nov. 28, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Lobenstine, E. C. 1929-1937. (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Lowdermilk, Walter Clay (Forest Research, U. of Nanking), 1925-1942. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Carbon of memorandum on erosion, runoff and vegetative cover conditions of the Hwai, Yi, and Shu River watersheds (Dec. 11, 1925). Typescript of study on the consequences of deforestation and slope cultivation. Later correspondence re: runoff studies. (WCL at Berkeley and Chief of Division of Research, Soil Conservation Service, USDA.)
- Correspondence -M- 1929-1948. (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Ministry of Finance; Ministry of Industry 1934. (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Miscellaneous 1925-1944. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Chinese language newspaper; typescript carbon copy of speech by Kiang [apparently Chiang Kai-Shek] at Nanching (Mar. 14, 1927).
- Moyer, Raymond T. 1929-1943. (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Myers, Clyde H. Jan.-May 1926. (Mainly carbons of HHL's letters to M.) (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Description of voyage from Marseilles to Shanghai; meets tea and rubber planters from India, Java, Penang, Borneo., Mar. 22, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - First impressions on arrival at Shanghai and Nanking., Apr. 10, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Myers, Clyde H. June 1926-1934. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Correspondence -K- 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 54)
- North, Dr. Eric M. 1924-1927. (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Correspondence -P- 1929-1949. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - 5 pp. mimeo Christmas letter from Frank W. Price and family, concerning various experiences during that year; revisit to Nanking - war devastation; journey from Shanghai to Chengtu in hinterland by steamer, train, and truck; migrations westward; air raids at Chungking; refugee aid, inoculation against cholera; wife's part of letter very full and colorful on truck ride from Kunming to Chengtu., Dec. 2, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Mimeo letter written from Shanghai after Communists came to power; have decided to stay on. (1 p. ), May 16, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Passport 1924-1929. (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Pen, S. C. Letter & article, 1937, re: rice yields. (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Pih, Ru Van 1928-1929. Wheat. (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Porter, R. H. 1925-Feb. 1927. Wheat and millet smut. (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Porter, R. H. Mar. 1927-1948. (Box 1, Folder 6l)
  On political and military situation in China (Dec. 28, 1926; Mar. 10, Apr. 9 [n.b., 8 pp.], and May 31, 1927); work in Paraguay (1946, 1948).
- Priest, Miss Elsie H. (see above, Folder 16), Nanking, China 1927-1930. (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Priest, Miss Elsie M. (see above, Folder 16), China 1931-1943. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Encl. Reisner's letter re: Outerbridge. Cf. Reisner folder below. Mimeo memorandum of J. L. Buck [q. v. ] on trip of Nanking faculty representative to North China in interest of furthering cooperation on agricultural projects., Jan. 16, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Correspondence -R- 1926-1948 (1924-1944) (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Reisner, J. E. Jan.-May 1926. (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Reisner, J. E. June-Aug. 1926. (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Reisner, J. H. Sept.-Dec. 1926. (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Reisner. J. H., Jan.-May 1927. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Carbon copy of letter from Reisner to Albert R. Mann re: developments in China since 1911., Feb. 16, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - To "dear friends" and to HHL re: ejection from Nanking, Mar. 19, Apr. 6, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Reisner, J. H., June 1927-Dec. 1927. (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Reisner, J. H., 1928. (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Reisner, J. H. 1929. (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Reisner. J. H. Jan.-May 1930. (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Reisner, J. H. June 1930-Feb. 1940. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Newsletter from Sierra Leone on African missions., July 9, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Reisner, J. H. Mar. 1940-Apr. 1950. (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Ritchey, G[eorge] E. Nov. 1925-Mar. 1926. Agronomy Dept., Nanking U., personal career plans and planting breeding. (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Ritchey, G. E. Apr. 1926-1947. Sane. (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Rose, Wickliffe 1925-1927. (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Correspondence -S- 1924-1947. (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Shen, E. K. Wuking, China, 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Shen, Mrs. L. Y. 1934-1937. (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Sie, Dean K.S., Dean of College of Agriculture, and Forestry, Nanking, 1930; Director, National Agricultural Research Bureau, Ministry of Industry, Shanghai, 1936. Mainly professional; mentions move to Chungking in 1938. With UNRRA in Washington, 1945.
  - 1934-1937. (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - 1938-l943. (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - 1945-1948. (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Slocum, Mr. & Mrs. Burl Alva (B.A. Slocum [CU '27-'28, '29, '30-'32 Grad] was an economic entomologist at U. of Nanking), 1934-1940. (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Some comment on the (J. Lossing and Pearl) Buck Family and other members of the Nanking community., Sept. 6, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Written from Chengtu, on Japanese raids on Chungking and Chengtu; concern about French Indo-China being cut off and future of the Burma route., July 5, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Smythe, Louis C., Nanking, China, 1935-1949. (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Mimeo Christmas letter; attempt to establish a "safety" zone in the area., Dec. 2, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - 3 pp. purple ditto letter from Nanking, reporting on student demonstrations, Communist agitation; [Nationalist] government bans on demonstrations, and secret police action; political discussions having been stilled earlier, students ripe for first agitator; tendency of Church to stress "personal piety and have little concern with the stirring issues of the day.", Apr. 3, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Steamers July 1924-Dec. 1929. (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Steamers Feb. 1930-Mar. 1931. (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Stevenson, Paul 1936-1938. (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Steward, Dr. & Mrs. An. N., Nanking, China 1925-1940 (+photos) (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Sze, Dr. S. K. Alfred 1929-1939. (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Correspondence -T- 1925-1947. (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Tai, S. E. Nanking, China, 1934-1946. (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Tang, S. Y. 1937-1941 +N. D. (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Thompson, J. C. 1930-1934. (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Thorp, James, Peiping, China 1934-1936. (Chief Soil Technologist with the National Geological Survey of China) (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Tsou, P. W. (CU grad, Dean of National SE University in Nanking; Ministry of Industry, Commerce and Labor, Shanghai, 1931; Cotton Industry Commission of National Economic Council, Shanghai, 1935; 1943+, Chungking and then rep. to UN Interim Commission on Food and Agriculture), 1925-1937. (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - On Japanese invasion of China. Various dates, reports on agricultural needs of China., Oct. 19, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Tsou, P. W., May 1943-Mar. 1944. (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Tsou, P. W., Apr. 1944-Oct. 1945. (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Tsou, P. W., Nov. 1945-Oct. 1944 +N. D. (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Correspondence -W- 1925-1947. (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Wang, S. C., 1929-1935. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Wang, Sheo, Nanking, China 1926-1940. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Ward, R. A., Nanking, China 1935-1937. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Warnshuis, A. A. 1930- (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Wheeler, R. H., Nanking, China 1934-1937. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Wiggans, R. G. Feb. 1927-May 1930 [Roy Glen Wiggans, CU, MS Agr. '1 Ph.D. '19] (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Wiggans, R. G. June 1930-Sept. 1930 + N. D. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Williams, J. E., Nanking, China, 1924-1926 [John Elias Williams, 1871-1927; see DAB.] (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence -X-Y-Z- 1934-1946 +Book. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Director, P. S. 1934-1940. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Yu, T. F., Hanking, China 1934-1945. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Yu, Tang Siang, University of Hanking, Hanking, China 1934-1935. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Zen, H. C. 1925-1936. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Materials Purchased and sent to China Mar. 1932-Feb. 1934. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Materials Purchased and sent to China Mar. 1934-May 1937. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous 1925-May 1929. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Misc. June 1929-Oct. 1929. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Misc. Dec. 1929-1930. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Misc. 1935-1937 + N. D. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Misc. N. D. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Chinese Trainees Jan.-June 1945. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Chinese Trainees July 1945. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Chinese Trainees Aug. 1945. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Chinese Trainees Sept. 1945. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Chinese Trainees Oct. 1945. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Chinese Trainees Nov. 1945. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Chinese Trainees 1946 +N. D. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Chinese Students 1945-Feb. 10, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Chinese Students Feb. 11 - Feb. 19, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Chinese Students Feb. 20-Feb. 31, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Chinese Students Mar. 1946. (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Chinese Students Apr. 1946. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Chinese Students May 1946. (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Chinese Students June - Dec. 1946. (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Chinese Students 1947 +N. D. + photos. (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Graduate School: Residence and Language Requirements 1941-1948. (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Graduate School: Lists of Degrees, Scholarships, Exams; Admissions 1941-1944. (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Graduate- Students Registered with Dr. Love 1942-1947. (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Graduate Students - Plant Breeding 1925-1944. (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Bell, F. Jameson 1940-1950. (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Seminar and Exam 1937-1946. (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Graduate School - Legislation, etc. 1934-1940. (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Reports to Graduate School - General 1936-1940. (Box 2, Folder 43)
- College Reports and Grades 1948. (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. 1923-1928. (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. 1930-1940. (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. 1941-1946. (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. N. D. (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. N. D. (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. N. D. (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Examinations, Problems, etc. N. D. (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Genetics 101 Problems N. D. (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Type Problems in Genetics 1934. (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Newspaper July 25, 1949. (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Data Papers 1940-1946. (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Data Papers 1947-1949. (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Data Papers N. D. (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Sze, Julia 1935. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  Mainly correspondence between Sao-ke Alfred Sze and HHL concerning daughter Julia's financial arrangements while a student at Cornell (Class of 1938) and later in New York City. Sze's letters contain occasional reference to the situation in China - Japanese incursions, severity of living conditions plight of refugees, and the like. Nb. Folders 59, 60.
- Sze, Julia Jan.-June 1938. (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Sze, Julia July- Dec. 1938. (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Sze, Julia 1939. (Box 2, Folder 6l)